Guide to the Andrew Wellington Cordier Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
Andrew Wellington Cordier Papers,
1918-1975
Cordier, Andrew W. (Andrew Wellington), 1901-
160 linear ft (ca. 202,520 items in 346 boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
4078651
The large collection covers all aspects of Cordier's life. It contains letters, memoranda, reports, cables, printed materials and photographs, mostly pertaining to his tenure at the United Nations and Columbia University.
Biographical Note
Andrew Wellington Cordier was born in Canton, Ohio in 1901. He died on Long Island in 1975. Cordier was educated at Manchester College in Indiana, (1923–44); the Univ. of Chicago; and the Graduate Institute of International Studies in Geneva.
From 1944 to 1946 he worked at the U.S. Dept. of State, after which he joined the United Nations, eventually serving as Executive Assistant to the UN secretaries general. He was a chief negotiator for the United Nations in the Congo in 1960. In 1962 he left the UN to become Dean of the School of International Affairs (SIA) at Columbia University. He served as acting President of Columbia in the years 1968 and 1969; later he was appointed President (1969–70). After leaving the Columbia presidency, Cordier returned to his position as Dean of SIA and served until 1972.
In 1970 Cordier was awarded the Alexander Hamilton medal, the university’s highest honor.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, documents, printed material, and photographs of Cordier. The papers cover three periods of Cordier's life: the early years, especially undergraduate and graduate school, as a professor at Manchester College in Indiana, and as a member of the U.S. State Dept.; the United Nations period, as a member of the Secretariat, and including the files of the Dag Hammarskjöld Foundation and working files for the publication of The Public Papers Of The Secretaries-General Of The United Nations; and the Columbia University period, containing Cordier's personal and working files during the time of his deanship and presidency. Among the prominent correspondents are Dag Hammarskjöld, Trygve Lie, Henry Cabot Lodge, Jr., Chester W. Nimitz, Lester B. Pearson, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Carlos P. Romulo, Eleanor Roosevelt, Adlai E. Stevenson, and Harry S. Truman.
Organization
The papers are organized in 11 series. The arrangement and list of the material in Boxes 39-202 is adapted from the work done on the files in Cordier's office.
Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
Series II: Catalogued Manuscripts, Documents and Photographs
Series III: 1923-1944
Series IV: 1930-1947
Series V: The United Nations Period And Related Files
Series VI: The Columbia University Period And Related Files
Series VII: Andrew W. Cordier Working Papers, 1971-1975
Series VIII: Honorary Degrees, Plaques, Awards and Honors
Series IX: Photographs, Printed and Miscellaneous Material
Series X: 1979 Addition
Series XI: 1980 Addition
Supplement to Cordier register (6,3/03). Regarding restricted items.
Subjects
Columbia University--Presidents.; Columbia University.--School of International Affairs.--Dean.; United Nations.--Secretary-General.; Manchester College (North Manchester, Ind.); United States.--Dept. of State.; Dag Hammarskjöld Foundation.; Hammarskjöld, Dag, 1905-1961.; Lie, Trygve, 1896-1968.; Lodge, Henry Cabot, 1902-1985.; Nimitz, Chester W. (Chester William), 1885-1966.; Pearson, Lester B.; Rockefeller, Nelson A. (Nelson Aldrich), 1908-1979.; Romulo, Carlos P. (Carlos Peña), 1899-1985.; Roosevelt, Eleanor, 1884-1962.; Stevenson, Adlai E. (Adlai Ewing), 1900-1965.; Truman, Harry S., 1884-1972.; International cooperation.; Education, Higher--United States.; Peace.; World politics.; International agencies.; Accounts.; Addresses.; Albums.; Announcements.; Appointment books.; Articles.; Awards.; Bibliographies.; Biographies.; Bluebrints.; Calendarts.; Clippings.; Contracts.; Directories.; Financial records.; Interviews.; Invitations.; Itineraries.; Lectures.; Manuals.; Memoranda.; Minutes.; Motion pictures.; Notebooks.; Passports.; Personnel records.; Phonodiscs.; Photoprints.; Plaques.; Press releases.; Programs.; Reports.; Syllabi.; Tape recordings.; Theses.; College administrators.; College presidents.; Diplomats.
Gift of Andrew W. Cordier, 1975, 1979, & 1980; transferred from the Lehman Library, 1977; gift of Doreen Geary, 1982.
Related Material
Certain University-related files are kept elsewhere in the University.
- Series I: Cataloged Correspondence
  - Acheson, Dean
  - Aldrich, Winthrop W.
  - Armstronp, Hamilton Fish
  - Austin, Warren R.
  - Baldwin, Roger Nash
  - Barnes, Djuna
  - Barzun, Jacques
  - Bing, Rudolf
  - Borton, Hugh
  - Bowles, Chester
  - Brown, John Mason
  - Brzezinski, Zbigniew
  - Bunche, Ralph J.
  - Burns, Arthur F.
  - Cadogan, Alexander G.M.
  - Canfield, Cass
  - Caradon, Hugh Mackintosh Foot, Baron
  - Carman, Harry J.
  - Cassals, Pablo
  - Cerf, Bennett A.
  - Childs, Marquis
  - Commanger, Henry Steele
  - Cordier, Andrew Wellington
  - Dillon, Douglas
  - Dobryain, Anatoly F.
  - Dodge, Cleveland E.
  - Eaton, Cyrus S.
  - Eban, Abba
  - Echaverria, Luis
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D.
  - Eisenhower, Mamie Doud
  - Eisenhower Milton S.
  - Fackenthl, Frank Diehl
  - Fairbanks, Douglas Elton, Jr.
  - Farley, .James A.
  - Firestone, Harvey S., Jr.
  - Ford, Henry, II
  - Fosdick, Raymond B.
  - Frost, Robert
  - Fulbright, J. W.
  - Gilchrist, Huntington
  - Hammarskjold, Dag
  - Harriman, Averell
  - Hearst, William Randolph, Jr.
  - Hiss, Alger
  - Hogan, Frank S.
  - Howard, Roy H.
  - Humphrey, Hubert Horatio
  - Jackson, B1trbara Ward (Lady)
  - Javits, Jacob K.
  - Jessup, Philip C.
  - Johnson, Lyndon B.
  - Kefauver, Estes
  - Kissinger, Henry Alfred
  - Knopf, Alfred A., Jr.
  - Koo, V.K. Wellington
  - Landon, Alf M.
  - Lasker, Mary (Mrs. Albert D.)
  - Lehman, Herbert H.
  - Lenya, Lotte
  - Lie, Trygve Halvdan
  - Lindsay, John Vliet
  - Lippmann, Walter
  - Lodge, Henry Cabot, .rr.
  - Lodge, John Davis
  - Luce, Clare Boothe
  - Luce, Henry R.
  - McCarthy, Eugene J.
  - McCloy, John ,J.
  - McCormack, John W.
  - McDonald, James G.
  - McGill, William J.
  - McGovern, George S.
  - Meany, George
  - Mesta, Perle
  - Miller, Arthur
  - Morris, Newbold
  - Moses, Robert
  - Muste, Abraham John
  - Mrydal, Alva (Mrs. Gunnar)
  - Myrdal, Gunnar
  - Nevins, Allan
  - Nimitz, Chester W.
  - O'Dwyer, William
  - Oppenheimer, Robert
  - Ormandy, Eugene
  - Paley, William S.
  - Pearson, Lester B.
  - Pell, Claiborne
  - Penney, James Cash
  - Piaget, Jean
  - Reuther, Walter P.
  - Robinson, Geroid T.
  - Rockefeller, David
  - Rockefeller, John D., Jr.
  - Rockefeller, John D., 3rd
  - Rockefeller, Nelson Aldrich
  - Romulo, Carlos P.
  - Roosevelt, Eleanor Roosevelt
  - Rusk, Dean
  - Sayre, Francis B.
  - Schapiro, Meyer
  - Seligman, Eustace
  - Shotwell, James T.
  - Sorensen, Theodore C.
  - Sparkman, John
  - Spellnmn, Francis Joseph, Cardinal
  - Steinbeck, John
  - Stettinius, lEdward R., Jr.
  - Stevenson, Adlai Ewin
  - Strauss, Anna Lord
  - Sulzberger, Arthur Hays
  - Sulzberger, Arthur Ochs
  - Swope, Herbert Bayard
  - Thackrey, T[heodore] O[lin]
  - Thant, U.
  - Truman, Harry S.
  - Vandenberg, Arthur H.
  - Wagner, Robert F.
  - Waldheim, Kurt
  - Watson, Thomas J.
  - Watson, Thomas J., Jr.
  - Welles, Sumner
  - Whalen, Grover A.
  - Wyzanski, Charles E., Jr.
- Series II Catalogued Manuscripts, Documents and Photographs
  - Bunche, Ralph J.
  - Dobrynin, Anatoly
  - Hammarskjold, Dag
  - Jessup, Philip C.
  - Lie, Trygve Halvan
  - Lippmann, Walter
  - Nimitz, Chester W.
  - Ormandy, Eugene
  - Pearson, Lester B.
  - Romulo, Carlos P.
  - Shotwell, James T.
  - Stevenson, Adlai E.
  - Thant, U
- Series III 1923 -1944
  - College Notebooks - 20 volumes (Box 1-3)
  - University of Chicago and Manchester College -Notes and Papers, n.d. (Box 4)
  - University of Chicago and Manchester College -Notes and Papers, 1923-1925 (Box 5)
  - Master's Thesis and Doctoral Dissertation - drafts and typescripts (Box 6)
  - Notes on a Trip to Europe, summer 1938 (Box 6)
  - "Study Manual for the Renaissance" (mimeograph booklet) (Box 6)
  - The American Seminar in Europe, 1928 (Box 6)
  - Syllabi, scrapbook and printed material by and about Cordier (Box 7)
- Series IV: 1930 -1947
  - Correspondence –General, 1930 -1936 (Box 8)
  - Correspondence –General, 1938 -1945 (with related items) (Box 9)
  - Correspondence –General, 1940 -1942 (Box 10)
  - Correspondence –General, 1943 -1947 (Box 11)
  - Church of the Brethren, 1930 -1944 (Box 12-13)
  - Midwest Institute of International Relations, 1940 (Box 14)
  - U.S. Department of State, 1944-1945 (Box 15)
  - U.N. Conference on International Organization, 1944-1947
    - Correspondence, memoranda, etc. (Box 16)
    - Telegrams, U.S. state Department (Box 16)
    - Minutes (a.mss.) (Box 16)
    - Notes (a.mss.) (Box 16)
    - Reports (t.mss.) (Box 16)
    - Report to the Secretary General... Economic Affairs, 1947 (Box 16)
    - Texts and Manuals, miscellaneous (Box 16)
    - The Dumbarton Oaks Proposals, with comments (Box 17)
    - Documents:
      - Commissions I &II (Box 18)
      - Commission II (Box 19)
      - Commission III (Box 20)
      - Commission IV (Box 21)
      - General -Lists of Documents and proposed amendments (Box 21)
      - General -Proposals Miscellaneous, (2 Folders) (Box 22)
      - Coordination Committee (Box 23)
      - Executive Committee (Box 23)
      - Journals and Orders of the Day (Box 23)
      - Plenary Sessions (Box 23)
      - Precis (Box 23)
      - Steering Committee (Box 23)
      - Mimeographs, Miscellaneous (Box 24)
    - Press Releases (Box 24)
    - Press and Opinion Summaries (Box 24)
    - Progress Reports on Commissions and Committees (Box 24)
    - U.S., Delegation: (Box 25)
      - Members, Organization, etc. (Box 25)
      - Manual (Box 25)
      - Daily Schedules (Box 25)
      - Press Releases (Box 25)
      - Typescripts and notes (Box 25)
      - Commission 11/1-2 (Box 25)
      - Commission 11/3-4 (Box 25)
    - U.S. Delegation -Meetings -Reports and Minutes Reports and miscellaneous mimeographs (Box 26)
    - Printed Material, (2 Folders) (Box 26)
  - Notes, manuscripts, documents, printed material -miscellaneous (Box 27)
  - Printed material (Box 28-29)
  - Manchester College Yearbooks (Box 30-31)
- Series V:The United Nations Period And Related Files
  - Subseries V.1: Invitations
    - 1956-1950 (Box 32)
    - 1951-1953 (Box 33)
    - 1953-1955 (Box 34)
    - 1956-1957 (Box 35)
    - 1958 -1959 (Box 36)
    - 1960 -1962 (Box 37)
    - Mixed Years (Box 38)
  - Subseries V.2: Personal Correspondence and Administrative Files of Cordier
    - Sub-subseries V.2.1: Personal Correspondence 1946-1962
      - 1946-1948 Personal correspondence: A-B (Box 39)
      - 1946-1948 Personal correspondence: C-F (Box 39)
      - 1946-1948 Personal correspondence: G-J (Box 39)
      - 1946-1948 Personal correspondence: K-O (Box 39)
      - 1946-1948 Personal correspondence: P-T (Box 39)
      - 1946-1948 Personal correspondence: U-Z (Box 39)
      - 1948-1949 Personal correspondence (chronological order) (Box 40)
      - 1952-1958 Autographs, photographs, requests for (only a few) (Box 40)
    - Sub-subseries V.2.2: Personal correspondence, 1950-1962 (alphabetically filed)
      - A Personal correspondence: "A" (Box 40)
      - Personal correspondence: Charles Allen 1955-1961 (Box 40)
      - Personal correspondence: (Box 40)
      - Personal correspondence: "Bea" (Box 40)
      - Personal correspondence: Paul Beam 1951-1954 (Box 40)
      - Personal correspondence! John V. Beamer 1952-1960 (Member of Congress) (Box 40)
      - Personal correspondence: "Beb -Bos" (Box 40)
      - Personal correspondence: Jacob Blaustein 1960-1962 Philanthropist (Box 41)
      - Personal Correspondence: David Blickenstaff 1955-1962 (Box 41)
      - Personal Correspondence: David Blickenstaff 1950-1960 (Box 41)
      - Personal Correspondence: Charles Boss Jr., Board of World Peace, Methodist Church, 1955-1960 (Box 41)
      - Personal Correspondence: "Bot" (Box 41)
      - Personal Correspondence: "Br" (Box 41)
      - Personal Correspondence: Church of the Brethren 1952-1961 (Box 41)
      - Personal Correspondence: Dr.J.D. Bright 1953 -1961 (Washburn Univ.) (Box 41)
      - Personal Correspondence: "Bu" (Box 41)
      - Personal Correspondence: Dr. E. H. Buehrig, Indiana University 1950-1962 (Box 41)
      - Personal Correspondence: "Ca" (Box 41)
      - Personal Correspondence: Curtis Campaign 1962 (Box 41)
      - Personal Correspondence: Carnegie Endowment for International Peace 1950 Personal Correspondence: "Ch" (Box 41)
      - Personal Correspondence: Waldo Chamberlin (UN, then New York Univ., then Dartmouth) 1956 -1961 (Box 41)
      - Personal Correspondence: Chicago, University of 1951-1961 (Box 41)
      - Personal Correspondence: "Cl" (Box 41)
      - Personal Correspondence: "Co" (Box 42)
      - Personal Correspondence: Columbia University, Oral History Research 1952 (Box 42)
      - Personal Correspondence: "Cr-" (Box 42)
      - Personal Correspondence: "Da" (Box 42)
      - Personal Correspondence: "De" (Box 42)
      - Personal Correspondence: "Di" (Box 42)
      - Personal Correspondence: "Do"-"Dr" (Box 42)
      - Personal Correspondence: "Mrs." Phyllis Dowling 1960-1962 (Box 42)
      - Personal Correspondence: "Du" (Box 42)
      - Personal Correspondence: "E" (Box 42)
      - Personal Correspondence: Dr. Kermit Eby, Professor of Social Sciences, Univ. of Chicago 1950-1962 (Box 42)
      - Personal Correspondence: Dr. Sherwood Eddy 1951 -1961 (Box 42)
      - Personal Correspondence: Judge Douglas Edmonds, Los Angeles 1954 -1962 Personal Correspondence: Dr. Calvert N. Ellis, President, Juniata College 1952-1962 (Box 42)
      - Personal Correspondence: "Fa-Fe" (Box 43)
      - Personal Correspondence: "Fi-Fl" (Box 43)
      - Personal Correspondence: "Fo" (Box 43)
      - Personal Correspondence: Wilder Foote 1956-1961 (Box 43)
      - Personal Correspondence: Robert Frost, poet. (Cordier luncheon, UN hq. (Box 43)
      - 17 March 1960 USSR poets, et al) (Box 43)
      - Personal Correspondence: "Ga-Gi" (Box 43)
      - Personal Correspondence: "Go" (Box 43)
      - Personal Correspondence: "Gr" (Box 43)
      - Personal Correspondence: Robert Gross, San Francisco 1955-1961 (was chairman UN Commemorative Con1955) (Box 43)
      - Personal Correspondence: Ernest A. Gross, New York 1953-1961 (was Deputy (Box 43)
      - Perm. Rep. USA to UN 1950-1952) (Box 43)
      - Personal Correspondence: "Ha" (Box 43)
      - Personal Correspondence: Dag Hammarskjold (1 personal telegram) (Box 43)
      - Personal Correspondence: "He" (Box 43)
      - Personal Correspondence: Dr. Blair Helman, President, Manchester College, 1956-1962 (Box 43)
      - "Hi" (Box 43)
      - "Ho" (Box 43)
      - "Hu" (Box 43)
      - Dr. Phil Jacob (U. of Penn.) and Betty Jacob 1950-1962 (Box 43)
      - "Je" (Box 43)
      - Judge Philip C. Jessup (1955-1962 (Int. Court, Columbia University, State Dept. etc.) (Box 43)
      - Personal Correspondence: Dr. Joseph E. Johnson (Carnegie Endowment, etc.) 1957-1961 (Box 43)
      - "Ka -Ke" (Box 44)
      - "Kh -Ki" (Box 44)
      - Dr. Grayson Kirk 1953 -1962 (President Emeritus, Columbia University) (Box 44)
      - Dr. Henry A. Kissinger 1953 -1953(Harvard Univ) (Box 44)
      - "Kl -Ko" (Box 44)
      - Dr. Joseph Korbel, Univ. of Denver 1949 -1961 (Box 44)
      - "Kr -" (Box 44)
      - "La" (Box 44)
      - York Langton, Minneapolis, Inn. 1950 -1961 (Box 44)
      - Dr.Walter Laves (Unesco, Indiana Univ. etc) 1953 -1962 (Box 44)
      - "Le" (Box 44)
      - "Li" (Box 44)
      - Walter Lippmann (writer, journalist) 1958 -1961 (Box 44)
      - Trygve Lie, 1953 -1960 (Sec Gen. of UN 1946-1953) (Box 44)
      - Mrs. Trygve Lie, death 1960 (Box 44)
      - Per Lind, 1961 and 1962 (Foreign Affairs, Sweden) (Box 44)
      - "Lo" (Box 44)
      - Henry Cabot Lodge 1955-1956 (formerly Permanent Rep;. of USA to the UN) "Lu" (Box 44)
      - "Ma" (Box 44)
      - "Me" (Box 44)
      - Dr. R. H. Miller, 1952-1959 Manchester College, North Manchester, Indiana (Box 44)
      - Mr. Richmond Miller, 1950-1962 (Quaker) (Box 44)
      - "Mo" (Box 45)
      - Robert Moses 1957-1962 (City of New York) (Box 45)
      - Motive Magazine re article on Cordier by Ines Long 1960 (Box 45)
      - "Mu" (Box 45)
      - "Mc" (Box 45)
      - "Na" (Box 45)
      - "Ne" (Box 45)
      - Earl Newsom, New York 1957-1960 (Box 45)
      - Hope Bedford Nevitt, Indianapolis, In. 1951 -1960 (Box 45)
      - Admiral Chester Nimitz, Berkeley, Cal. 1950-1961 (Box 45)
      - "No" (Box 45)
      - "O" (Box 46)
      - Dr. Glenn Olds, 1957-1961 (President Springfield College) (Box 46)
      - "Pa" (Box 46)
      - Hon. Richard C. Patterson Jr., 1957-1962(City of New York) (Box 46)
      - "Pe" (Box 46)
      - Hon. Lester B. Pearson. 1952-1962 (Canadian Prime Minister, Assembly President, etc.) (Box 46)
      - Mr. Adrian Pelt 1951 -1962 (World Federation UN Associations, Head, European Office, UN in Geneva, etc.) (Box 46)
      - Personal Correspondence: "Ph" (Box 46)
      - Personal Correspondence: Puerto Rican Cultural Center Inc. 1957-1960 (La Hermosa) (Box 46)
      - "Q" (Box 46)
      - "Ra" (Box 46)
      - "Re -Rh" (Box 46)
      - "Ri" (Box 46)
      - Gerald Riddell Memorial 1954 (Canada, Dept. Ext. Relations) (Box 46)
      - "Ro" (Box 46)
      - Honorable Nelson A. Rockefeller 1952-1962 (Box 46)
      - General Carlos P. Romulo 1950 -1959 (Philippines) (Box 46)
      - Eleanor Roosevelt (Mrs. Franklin D.) 1950-1961 (Box 47)
      - Leo Rosenthal 1958-1959 (photographer) (Box 47)
      - Mr. C. Easton Rothwell 1950-1958 (Director Hoover Institute and Library) Harold Row 1950-1961 (Church of the Brethren) (Box 47)
      - "Ru" (Box 47)
      - Dr. Howard Rusk 1959-1962 (Institute of Physical Medicine, NYCity) (Box 47)
      - "Sa" (Box 47)
      - "Sch" (Box 47)
      - Dr. V. Schwalm, North Manchester, Indiana 1950 -1962 Note: Dr. Cordier's letters to Dr. Schwalm, who was a close personal friend, could be considered as a continuous diary of personal and official events from 1950 to 1962 when Dr. Cordier left the UN Secretariat. (Box 47)
      - "Se" (Box 47)
      - Shiv Shastri 1960-1962 (former UN staff member) (Box 47)
      - "Si" (Box 47)
      - "Sl -" (Box 48)
      - "Sm" (Box 48)
      - "Sn" (Box 48)
      - "So –Sp" (Box 48)
      - Dr. Ralph W. Sockman 1956 -1962 (Minister Christ Church Methodist NY City) (Box 48)
      - "Sta-Ste" (Box 48)
      - Honorable Adlai Stevenson 1950 -1962 (Perm Rep of the USA to the UN, etc.) (Box 48)
      - "Sti" - "Sto" (Box 48)
      - Helen Stokel1 (Mrs. Hager) 1950-1952 (Box 48)
      - William Stoneman, 1960-1962 (Chicago Daily News; ) formerly Secretariat staff member) (Box 48)
      - Sam Stoner 1953-1962 (Enid, Oklahoma) (Box 48)
      - "Str" (Box 48)
      - Arthur Sweetzer 1954-1962 (Washington, D.C.) (Box 48)
      - "Ta -Ti" (Box 48)
      - "Tr" (Box 48)
      - "U" .. (Box 48)
      - U.N. -Salary, Leave, Allowances, etc. -AWC (Box 48)
      - "Ya" (Box 48)
      - Dr. Eelco Yan Kleffens (t955 -1961) (Pres. General Assembly 1955) (Box 48)
      - "Ye " (Box 48)
      - Abraham Yereide 1950 -1960 (International Council) for Christian Leadership) (Box 48)
      - "Wa" (Box 49)
      - Harry Walker Inc., (lecture agent) 1961-1962 (Box 49)
      - "We" (Box 49)
      - Dr. Herman B. Wells 1951-1962 (President, Indiana Univ) (Box 49)
      - Dan West 1950-1962 (Heifer Project Inc Goshen, Ind.) (Box 49)
      - "Wh" (Box 49)
      - "Wi" (Box 49)
      - "Wo -" (Box 49)
      - "X" (Box 49)
      - "Y" (Box 49)
      - "Z" (Box 49)
      - Dr. M. R. Zigler. 1950-1961 (Brethren Service Commission European program) (Box 49)
    - Sub-subseries V.2.3.: Personal files re Transition of Posts Period 1961-1962
      (i.e. resignation from United Nations and taking up of Columbia University post)
      - Blickenstaff letter, 8 July 1961 (Box 50)
      - Career memo, 1961 (Box 50)
      - Correspondence with Secretaries-General Hammarskjöld and U Thant 1961-1962 (Box 50)
      - Documentation on Organization of the Secretariat 1961-1962 (Box 50)
      - Legal Counsel Memorandum re Cordier separation emoluments (Box 50)
      - Messages and tributes to Cordier 1961-1962, (3 Folders) (Box 50)
      - Miscellaneous correspondence March-April 1962 (re Ford Foundation. (trip); US Committee of Dag Hammarskjold Foundation; etc. (Box 50)
      - Press comment, 1961-1962 (Box 51)
      - Press Releases (UN) and SG press conference (1961-1962) (Box 51)
      - Text of Cordier farewell message to the staff for UN Secretariat News New York City, Mayor's luncheon for Mr. Cordier, 20 March 1962 (Box 51)
      - Secretary-General U Thant's luncheon for Mr. Cordier, 28 February 1962 (Box 51)
      - United States Mission to the United Nations; reception for Mr. Cordier, 27 Feb 1962 (signature book only) (Box 51)
      - UN Press Section party (Signature card only, no date) (Box 51)
      - UN 20rrespondents Association (press); luncheon 12 February 1962 (1 letter on file) (Box 51)
      - UN Staff reception for Mr. Cordier, 21 February 1962 press release, announcement, thank you messages, signature) book (Box 51)
      - United States Committee for the United Nations -­luncheon 19 March 1962 (correspondence) (Box 51)
    - Sub-subseries V.2.4: Chronological Files 1950(?)-1962
      Note: These files contain copies of official and personal communications of both a confidential and non-confidential nature prepared by Mr. Cordier, or by others, for his signature or that of the Secretaries General
      - Chronological file: Prior to 19501 NU? (Box 52)
      - Chronological file: 1950 (missing?) (Box 52)
      - Chronological file: Jan-Mar 1951 (Box 52)
      - Chronological file: Apr-Jun 1951 (Box 52)
      - Chronological file: Jul-Sep 1951 (Box 52)
      - Chronological file: Oct-Dec 1951 (Box 52)
      - Chronological file: Jan-Mar 1952 (Box 52)
      - Chronological file: Apr-Jun 1952 (Box 52)
      - Chronological file: Jul-Sep 1952 (Box 52)
      - Chronological file: Oct-Dec 1952 (Box 52)
      - Chronological file: Jan-Mar 1953 (Box 52)
      - Chronological file: Apr-Jun 1953 (Box 52)
      - Chorological file: Jul-Sep 1953 (Box 52)
      - Chronological file: Oct-Dec 1953 (Box 52)
      - Chronological file: Jan-Mar 1954 (Box 53)
      - Chronological file: Apr-Jun 1954 (Box 53)
      - Chronological file: Jul-Sep 1954 (Box 53)
      - Chronological file: Oct-Dec 1954 (Box 53)
      - Chronological file: Jan-Mar 1955 (Box 53)
      - Chronological file: Apr-Jun 1955 (Box 53)
      - Chronological file: Jul-Sep 1955 (Box 53)
      - Chronological file: Oct-Dec 1955 (Box 53)
      - Chronological file: Jan-Mar 1956 (Box 53)
      - Chronological file: Apr-Jun 1956 (Box 53)
      - Chronological file: Jul-Sep 1956 (Box 53)
      - Chronological file: Oct-Dec 1956 (Box 53)
      - Chronological file: Jan-Mar 1957 (Box 54)
      - Chronological file: Apr-Jun 1957 (Box 54)
      - Chronological file: Jul-Sep, 1957 (Box 54)
      - Chronological file: Oct-Dec 1957 (Box 54)
      - Chorological file: Jan-Mar 1958 (Box 54)
      - Chronological file: Apr-Jun 1958 (Box 54)
      - Chronological file: Jul-Sep 1958 (Box 54)
      - Chronological file: Oct-Dec 1958 (Box 54)
      - Chronological file: Jan-Mar 1959 (Box 55)
      - Chronological file: Apr-Jun 1959 (Box 55)
      - Chronological file: Jul-Sep 1959 (Box 55)
      - Chronological file: Oct-Dec 1959 (Box 55)
      - Chronological file: Jan-Mar 1960 (Box 55)
      - Chronological file: Apr-Jun 1960 (Box 55)
      - Chronological file: Jul-Sep 1960 (Box 55)